Prepare for the ride of your life.
Extraction 2 is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Sam Hargrave.
Back from the brink of death, highly skilled commando Tyler Rake takes on another
dangerous mission: saving the imprisoned family of a ruthless gangster.
Tyler Rake, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Nik Khan, played by Golshifteh Farahani.
Yaz Khan, played by Adam Bessa.
Zurab Radiani / Nikoloz Radiani, played by Tornike Gogrichiani.
David Radiani, played by Tornike Bziava.
Ketevan Radiani, played by Tinatin Dalakishvili.
Extraction 2 is a 2023 American action thriller film directed by Sam Hargrave
and written by Joe Russo, based on the graphic novel Ciudad.
It is the second installment in the Extraction franchise.
Chris Hemsworth, Golshifteh Farahani and Adam Bessa reprise their roles from the first film, while Tornike Gogrichiani,
Tornike Bziava, Tinatin Dalakishvili, Daniel Bernhardt, Olga Kurylenko and Idris Elba appear in pivotal roles.
In the film, Tyler Rake is initially hired to rescue the
family of a crime lord from a prison in Georgia.
Following the successful debut of the first film, Netflix announced a sequel in May 2020 with Joe Russo
returning to write, Hargrave returning to direct and Hemsworth returning in the lead.
By December, Joe and his brother Anthony hoped that the sequel would
develop the characters enough to start a cinematic universe.
Filming was scheduled to begin in Sydney in September 2021, but was delayed by the COVID-19 pandemic
and eventually started in Prague in November, before concluding in Vienna in April 2022.
In addition to the returns of the Russos, Hargrave and Hemsworth, Henry
Jackman and Alex Belcher returned to compose the score.
Extraction 2 was released by Netflix on June 16,
2023 to positive reviews from critics.
The film was nominated for Best Stunts (Action) at the 6th
Hollywood Critics Association Midseason Film Awards.
The film explores themes of assassin, hero, escape, explosive, mercenary.
The tone is dark and intense.